VICTOR SANAVIA

E-mail: vsanaviaf@pm.me
Tel: +51 997 552 685
www.linkedin.com/in/vsanavia

SUMMARY

Open for remote work.

IT industry professional with deep expertise on cloud, security and IT process automation, which makes me a great asset for any organization working on Digital Transformation. Highly motivated on working for demanding organizations with focus on solving very difficult problems that will provide high ROI for its customers.

JOB EXPERIENCE

Independent Advisor: Jan 2021 - Current

Lima, Peru

- Advising partners on business plans focused on recurring revenue products, mainly related to cloud based services and software.
- Planning and deploying a cloud based platform for a reputation based product.
- Successfully submitting a full stack service and multi cloud architecture for the <u>Cloud Resume Challenge</u>.

Sales Engineer - Cisco Systems, Inc.: Aug 2020 – Dec 2020 Lima, Peru

- Working with local SPs on developing offerings such as SD-WAN, Endpoint Security as a Service, Multi factor authentication and DNS based protection.
- Coordinating bidding processes for inventory build-up between partners and SPs.
- Leading architectural engagement with key customers to assess opportunities for Application Performance Management (APM) on their cloud based workloads (Azure, AWS, etc.)

Virtual Sales Account Manager – Cisco Systems, Inc.: Oct 2018 – Jul 2020 Lima, Peru

- Build-up of pipeline on (SMB) accounts with low penetration using social media, cold calling and website analytics. Identifying key personas, demand generation via social media and managing relationship between customers and partners.
- Leading extended team to increase revenue 110% YoY on commercial accounts on my territory.
- Increasing penetration of software-based solutions (Collaboration, Security, Datacenter; approximately 40%) for accounts on my territory.

Business Development Manager – Sonda del Peru: May 2017 – July 2018 Lima, Peru

- Working as Point-of-Contact with Cisco to ensure sales quotas are met. This involves
 creating joint marketing plans, development of innovative software based product offerings (UC as a Service, UCS, etc.) and day-to-day communications with Cisco sales.
- Engaging medium accounts to increase Sonda's wallet penetration on the Peruvian IT enterprise market.

Creation of strategy based on BI dashboards to evaluate Pipeline/Forecast behavior. This
information helped Sonda's leadership team on qualifying sales execution and drive continuous improvement on business engagements.

Technical Account Manager – Anida Consultores: Nov 2016 – Apr 2017 Lima, Peru

- Develop and position new service offerings for large service provider, including detailed business plans and creation of marketing assets for service provider sales and presales.
- Explain benefits of observability solutions delivered by integration of open source and commercial software
- Architect APM solution for healthcare mobile application (including instrumentation deployment strategy, threshold identification and reporting)

Sales Engineer – Hewlett Packard Enterprise HPE Software: Jul 2015 - Oct 2016 Lima, Peru

- Serving as technical advisor for complex Cloud and Automation opportunities across Latin America. Communicating cloud strategy to executives of key accounts.
- Develop strategies for customers with regard to cloud services architectures and automation deployment.
- Deployment of analytics platform on service provider accounts to exploit Machine Learning to anticipate/forecast failures.
- Architect continuous delivery testing practices that encompass service virtualization, performance and functional testing for development environments.

Sales Engineer – Hewlett-Packard HP Software.: Feb 2013 – Jun 2015 Caracas, Venezuela

- Leading presales technical fulfillment of HP Software Enterprise Licensing Agreements for large financial institutions and Service Providers.
- Providing architectural guidelines for complex technical engagements for opportunities on MCA region.

Sales Engineer – Hewlett-Packard HP Networking: Aug 2010 – Jan 2013 Caracas, Venezuela

- Responsible for starting business operation for HP Networking on the Venezuelan market. Consistent revenue growth of 30% YoY over the time period.
- Led standardization initiative with SP to include HP Networking as Customer Premises Equipment.

Technical Consultant - Sincor (Joint Venture Total/PDVSA/Statoil): Oct 2001 - Dec 2007

- Design and operate enterprise network including WAN, LAN and remote access. Ensure SLO were met using available resources.
- Rearchitect OT network to meet 99.995% yearly availability goal.
- Develop enterprise security policies and continuously adapt them to meet new business requirements and potential weaknesses/threats.

EDUCATION

1999 - Bachelor of Engineering, Electronic Engineer, Universidad Simón Bolivar, Venezuela

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Solutions Architect Associate, ID XQDTKQKJCNFE179C, April 2021
- TOGAF 9 Foundation, License Number 100611 October 2014